Guide to the Pat Williams Papers 1979-1997
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
- Legislative, 1979-1996; Series II; 22.5 linear feet
  - Subseries 15: Voting Record
    - 97th Congress, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 93/3)
    - 98th Congress, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 93/4)
    - 99th Congress, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 93/5)
    - 99th Congress, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 93/6)
    - 99th Congress, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 94/1)
    - 100th Congress, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 94/2)
    - 100th Congress, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 94/3)
    - 100th Congress, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 94/4)
    - 100th Congress, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 94/5)
    - 101st Congress, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 94/6)
    - 101st Congress, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 95/1)
    - 101st Congress, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 95/2)
    - 101st Congress, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 95/3)
    - 102nd Congress, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 95/4)
    - 102nd Congress, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 95/5)
- Speeches and Writings, 1979-1996; Series III; 1.5 linear feet
  This series includes the texts of speeches presented before bodies such as the Montana Senate and House, the National Congress of American Indians, the American Bar Association, the National Community Action Foundation, and his responses to selected weekly Presidential radio addresses. The Congressional Record section includes photocopies of Williams' statements from that publication; these were gathered, copied, and listed by Williams' staff, and there is an index by topic and date at the beginning of each folder. There are a few Special Order Statements.
  The series is subdivided into three subseries: Speeches, Congressional Record, and Special order statements. Speeches are arranged chronologically, except for two folders, "Forest Speeches," and "Toast to Texas," and a few undated speeches; Congressional Record is arranged chronologically by congressional session number; and special order statements are chronological.
  - Subseries 1: Congressional Record
    - 97th Congress, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 96/1)
    - 98th Congress, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 96/2)
    - 98th Congress, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 96/3)
    - 99th Congress, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 96/4)
    - 99th Congress, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 96/5)
    - 100th Congress, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 96/6)
    - 101st Congress, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 96/7)
    - 101st Congress, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 96/8)
    - 102nd Congress, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 96/9)
    - 102nd Congress, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 96/10)
    - 103rd Congress, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 97/1)
    - 103rd Congress, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 97/2)
    - 104th Congress, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 97/3)
    - 104th Congress, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 97/4)
  - Subseries 2: Special Order Statements
    - 1979-1996 (Box-folder 97/5)
  - Subseries 3: Speeches
    - 1979-1982 (Box-folder 97/6)
    - 1983-1984 (Box-folder 97/7)
    - 1985-1986 (Box-folder 97/8)
    - 1987-1988 (Box-folder 97/9)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 97/10)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 97/11)
    - 1991 (Box-folder 98/1)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 98/2)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 98/3)
    - 1994 (Box-folder 98/4)
    - 1995-1996 (Box-folder 98/5)
    - 1979-1980 (Box-folder 98/6)
    - undated (Box-folder 98/7)
    - Forest Speeches, 1984-1990 (Box-folder 98/8)
    - Toast to Texas (Box-folder 98/9)
- Press Releases, 1979-1987; Series IV; 0.5 linear feet
  This series consists of press releases issued in the U.S. and Montana by Williams' office. The releases offer a digest of Williams' legislative actions, reactions to events, and excerpts from his congressional testimony and addresses. Most are photocopies from originals.
  The series is arranged chronologically.
  - 1979-1982 (Box-folder 99/1)
  - 1981-1982 (Box-folder 99/2)
  - 1983 (Box-folder 99/3)
  - 1983-1984 (Box-folder 99/4)
  - 1987 (Box-folder 99/5)
- Scheduling, 1979-1996; Series V; 4.5 linear feet
  This series is composed of Congressman Williams' travel schedules and contains hourly, daily, and weekly schedules, correspondence, and maps. There are separate sections for general travel and for travel in the District of Columbia.
  - Travel, 1979 (Box-folder 100/1)
  - Travel, 1980 Jan-May (Box-folder 100/2)
  - Travel, 1980 Jun-Dec (Box-folder 100/3)
  - Travel, 1981 (Box-folder 100/4)
  - Travel, 1982 Jan-July (Box-folder 100/5)
  - Travel, 1982 Aug-Dec (Box-folder 100/6)
  - Travel, 1983 Jan-May (Box-folder 101/1)
  - Travel, 1983 Jun-Aug (Box-folder 101/2)
  - Travel, 1983 Sept-Dec (Box-folder 101/3)
  - Travel, 1984 Jan-March (Box-folder 101/4)
  - Travel, 1984 April-May (Box-folder 101/5)
  - Travel, 1984 July (Box-folder 101/6)
  - Travel, 1984 Aug-Dec (Box-folder 101/7)
  - Travel, 1985 Jan-July (Box-folder 102/1)
  - Travel, 1985 Aug-Dec (Box-folder 102/2)
  - Travel, 1986 Jan-May (Box-folder 102/3)
  - Travel, 1986 June-Dec (Box-folder 102/4)
  - Travel, 1987 Jan-June (Box-folder 102/5)
  - Travel, 1987 July-Dec (Box-folder 102/6)
  - Travel, 1988 (Box-folder 103/1)
  - Travel, 1989 Jan-April (Box-folder 103/2)
  - Travel, 1989 May-Dec (Box-folder 103/3)
  - Travel, 1990 Jan-April (Box-folder 103/4)
  - Travel, 1990 May-July (Box-folder 103/5)
  - Travel, 1990 Aug-Dec (Box-folder 103/6)
  - Travel, 1991 Jan-Feb (Box-folder 103/7)
  - Travel, 1991 March-May (Box-folder 103/8)
  - Travel, 1991 June (Box-folder 104/1)
  - Travel, 1991 July (Box-folder 104/2)
  - Travel, 1991 Aug (Box-folder 104/3)
  - Travel, 1991 Sept-Dec (Box-folder 104/4)
  - Travel, 1992 Jan (Box-folder 104/5)
  - Travel, 1992 Feb-March (Box-folder 104/6)
  - Travel, 1992 April (Box-folder 104/7)
  - Travel, 1992 May-June (Box-folder 104/8)
  - Travel, 1992 July (Box-folder 104/9)
  - Travel, 1992 Aug (Box-folder 105/1)
  - Travel, 1992 Sept (Box-folder 105/2)
  - Travel, 1992 Oct-Dec (Box-folder 105/3)
  - Travel, 1993 Jan-March (Box-folder 105/4)
  - Travel, 1993 April-Sept (Box-folder 105/5)
  - Travel, 1993 Oct-Dec (Box-folder 105/6)
  - Travel, 1994 Jan-March (Box-folder 105/7)
  - Travel, 1994 April (Box-folder 105/8)
  - Travel, 1994 May-Sept (Box-folder 106/1)
  - Travel, 1994 Oct-Dec (Box-folder 106/2)
  - Travel, 1995 Jan-July (Box-folder 106/3)
  - Travel, 1995 Aug-Dec (Box-folder 106/4)
  - Travel, 1996 (Box-folder 106/5)
  - DC, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 107/1)
  - DC, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 107/2)
  - DC, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 107/3)
  - DC, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 107/4)
  - DC, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 107/5)
  - DC, 1989 (Box-folder 108/1)
  - DC, 1990 (Box-folder 108/2)
  - DC, 1991 (Box-folder 108/3)
  - DC, 1992 (Box-folder 108/4)
  - DC, 1993 (Box-folder 108/5)
  - DC, 1994 (Box-folder 108/6)
  - DC, 1996 (Box-folder 108/7)
- Clippings, 1981-1996; Series VI; 14.0 linear feet
  This series consists of newspaper clippings from Montana newspapers. Materials were collected on political issues from December 1978 to November 1996 by Williams' staff. Most of the articles are directly concerned with Montana, including the long-debated Wilderness Bill. Other issues include the Alaska Land Bill, the Chicago and Milwaukee Railroad, Amtrak, the Libby Dam project, ARCO, the Federal Aviation Administration, and other concerns of Montanans.
  The series is arranged chronologically by month and year.
  - December, 1978 (Box-folder 109/1)
  - January, 1979 (Box-folder 109/2)
  - February, 1979 (Box-folder 109/3)
  - March, 1979 (Box-folder 109/4)
  - April, 1979 (Box-folder 109/5)
  - May, 1979 (Box-folder 109/6)
  - June, 1979 (Box-folder 109/7)
  - July, 1979 (Box-folder 109/8)
  - August, 1979 (Box-folder 109/9)
  - September, 1979 (Box-folder 109/10)
  - October, 1979 (Box-folder 109/11)
  - November, 1979 (Box-folder 110/1)
  - December, 1979 (Box-folder 110/2)
  - January, 1980 (Box-folder 110/3)
  - January, 1980 (Box-folder 110/4)
  - February, 1980 (Box-folder 110/5)
  - February, 1980 (Box-folder 110/6)
  - March, 1980 (Box-folder 110/7)
  - March, 1980 (Box-folder 110/8)
  - April, 1980 (Box-folder 110/9)
  - April, 1980 (Box-folder 110/10)
  - May, 1980 (Box-folder 110/11)
  - May, 1980 (Box-folder 110/12)
  - June, 1980 (Box-folder 111/1)
  - June, 1980 (Box-folder 111/2)
  - July, 1980 (Box-folder 111/3)
  - August, 1980 (Box-folder 111/4)
  - August, 1980 (Box-folder 111/5)
  - September, 1980 (Box-folder 111/6)
  - September, 1980 (Box-folder 111/7)
  - October, 1980 (Box-folder 111/8)
  - October, 1980 (Box-folder 111/9)
  - October, 1980 (Box-folder 111/10)
  - November, 1980 (Box-folder 111/11)
  - December, 1980 (Box-folder 111/12)
  - January, 1981 (Box-folder 112/1)
  - February, 1981 (Box-folder 112/2)
  - March, 1981 (Box-folder 112/3)
  - April, 1981 (Box-folder 112/4)
  - April, 1981 (Box-folder 112/5)
  - May, 1981 (Box-folder 112/6)
  - June, 1981 (Box-folder 112/7)
  - July, 1981 (Box-folder 112/8)
  - August, 1981 (Box-folder 112/9)
  - September, 1981 (Box-folder 113/1)
  - October, 1981 (Box-folder 113/2)
  - November, 1981 (Box-folder 113/3)
  - December, 1981 (Box-folder 113/4)
  - January, 1982 (Box-folder 113/5)
  - February, 1982 (Box-folder 113/6)
  - March, 1982 (Box-folder 113/7)
  - April, 1982 (Box-folder 114/1)
  - May, 1982 (Box-folder 114/2)
  - June, 1982 (Box-folder 114/3)
  - June, 1982 (Box-folder 114/4)
  - July, 1982 (Box-folder 114/5)
  - August, 1982 (Box-folder 114/6)
  - August, 1982 (Box-folder 114/7)
  - September, 1982 (Box-folder 114/8)
  - October, 1982 (Box-folder 115/1)
  - October, 1982 (Box-folder 115/2)
  - November, 1982 (Box-folder 115/3)
  - December, 1982 (Box-folder 115/4)
  - January-December, 1983 (Box-folder 115/5)
  - January, 1984 (Box-folder 115/6)
  - February, 1984 (Box-folder 115/7)
  - March, 1984 (Box-folder 115/8)
  - April, 1984 (Box-folder 115/9)
  - May, 1984 (Box-folder 115/10)
  - June, 1984 (Box-folder 115/11)
  - July, 1984 (Box-folder 115/12)
  - August, 1984 (Box-folder 116/1)
  - September, 1984 (Box-folder 116/2)
  - October, 1984 (Box-folder 116/3)
  - November, 1984 (Box-folder 116/4)
  - December, 1984 (Box-folder 116/5)
  - January, 1985 (Box-folder 116/6)
  - February, 1985 (Box-folder 116/7)
  - March, 1985 (Box-folder 116/8)
  - April, 1985 (Box-folder 116/9)
  - May, 1985 (Box-folder 116/10)
  - June, 1985 (Box-folder 116/11)
  - July, 1985 (Box-folder 116/12)
  - August, 1985 (Box-folder 117/1)
  - September, 1985 (Box-folder 117/2)
  - October, 1985 (Box-folder 117/3)
  - November, 1985 (Box-folder 117/4)
  - December, 1985 (Box-folder 117/5)
  - January, 1986 (Box-folder 117/6)
  - February, 1986 (Box-folder 117/7)
  - March, 1986 (Box-folder 117/8)
  - April, 1986 (Box-folder 117/9)
  - May, 1986 (Box-folder 117/10)
  - June, 1986 (Box-folder 117/11)
  - July, 1986 (Box-folder 117/12)
  - July, 1986 (Box-folder 118/1)
  - August, 1986 (Box-folder 118/2)
  - August, 1986 (Box-folder 118/3)
  - September, 1986 (Box-folder 118/4)
  - October, 1986 (Box-folder 118/5)
  - October, 1986 (Box-folder 118/6)
  - November, 1986 (Box-folder 118/7)
  - December, 1986 (Box-folder 118/8)
  - January, 1987 (Box-folder 118/9)
  - February, 1987 (Box-folder 119/1)
  - March, 1987 (Box-folder 119/2)
  - April, 1987 (Box-folder 119/3)
  - June, 1987 (Box-folder 119/4)
  - July, 1987 (Box-folder 119/5)
  - August, 1987 (Box-folder 119/6)
  - September, 1987 (Box-folder 119/7)
  - September, 1987 (Box-folder 119/8)
  - October, 1987 (Box-folder 119/9)
  - October, 1987 (Box-folder 120/1)
  - November, 1987 (Box-folder 120/2)
  - December, 1987 (Box-folder 120/3)
  - December, 1987 (Box-folder 120/4)
  - January, 1988 (Box-folder 120/5)
  - February, 1988 (Box-folder 120/6)
  - March, 1988 (Box-folder 120/7)
  - April, 1988 (Box-folder 120/8)
  - May, 1988 (Box-folder 121/1)
  - June, 1988 (Box-folder 121/2)
  - July, 1988 (Box-folder 121/3)
  - August, 1988 (Box-folder 121/4)
  - September, 1988 (Box-folder 121/5)
  - October, 1988 (Box-folder 121/6)
  - October, 1988 (Box-folder 122/1)
  - November, 1988 (Box-folder 122/2)
  - December, 1988 (Box-folder 122/3)
  - January, 1989 (Box-folder 122/4)
  - February, 1989 (Box-folder 122/5)
  - March, 1989 (Box-folder 122/6)
  - April, 1989 (Box-folder 122/7)
  - May, 1989 (Box-folder 122/8)
  - June, 1989 (Box-folder 123/1)
  - July, 1989 (Box-folder 123/2)
  - August, 1989 (Box-folder 123/3)
  - September, 1989 (Box-folder 123/4)
  - October, 1989 (Box-folder 123/5)
  - November, 1989 (Box-folder 123/6)
  - November, 1989 (Box-folder 123/7)
  - December, 1989 (Box-folder 123/8)
  - January, 1990 (Box-folder 124/1)
  - February, 1990 (Box-folder 124/2)
  - March, 1990 (Box-folder 124/3)
  - April, 1990 (Box-folder 124/4)
  - May, 1990 (Box-folder 124/5)
  - May, 1990 (Box-folder 124/6)
  - June, 1990 (Box-folder 125/1)
  - June, 1990 (Box-folder 125/2)
  - July, 1990 (Box-folder 125/3)
  - July, 1990 (Box-folder 125/4)
  - August, 1990 (Box-folder 125/5)
  - September, 1990 (Box-folder 125/6)
  - October, 1990 (Box-folder 125/7)
  - October, 1990 (Box-folder 126/1)
  - November, 1990 (Box-folder 126/2)
  - December, 1990 (Box-folder 126/3)
  - January, 1991 (Box-folder 126/4)
  - February, 1991 (Box-folder 126/5)
  - March, 1991 (Box-folder 126/6)
  - April, 12791 (Box-folder 127/1)
  - May, 12791 (Box-folder 127/2)
  - May, 12791 (Box-folder 127/3)
  - June, 12791 (Box-folder 127/4)
  - June, 12791 (Box-folder 127/5)
  - July, 12791 (Box-folder 127/6)
  - July, 1991 (Box-folder 127/7)
  - August, 1991 (Box-folder 128/1)
  - August, 1991 (Box-folder 128/2)
  - September, 1991 (Box-folder 128/3)
  - October, 1991 (Box-folder 128/4)
  - November, 1991 (Box-folder 128/5)
  - December, 1991 (Box-folder 129/1)
  - January, 1992 (Box-folder 129/2)
  - February, 1992 (Box-folder 129/3)
  - March, 1992 (Box-folder 129/4)
  - April, 1992 (Box-folder 129/5)
  - May, 1992 (Box-folder 129/6)
  - May, 1992 (Box-folder 129/7)
  - June, 1992 (Box-folder 129/8)
  - June, 1992 (Box-folder 130/1)
  - June, 1992 (Box-folder 130/2)
  - July, 1992 (Box-folder 130/3)
  - August, 1992 (Box-folder 130/4)
  - September, 1992 (Box-folder 130/5)
  - October, 1992 (Box-folder 130/6)
  - October, 1992 (Box-folder 130/7)
  - October, 1992 (Box-folder 130/8)
  - November, 1992 (Box-folder 131/1)
  - December, 1992 (Box-folder 131/2)
  - January, 1993 (Box-folder 131/3)
  - February, 1993 (Box-folder 131/4)
  - February, 1993 (Box-folder 131/5)
  - March, 1993 (Box-folder 131/6)
  - April, 1993 (Box-folder 131/7)
  - May, 1993 (Box-folder 132/1)
  - May, 1993 (Box-folder 132/2)
  - June, 1993 (Box-folder 132/3)
  - June, 1993 (Box-folder 132/4)
  - July, 1993 (Box-folder 132/5)
  - August, 1993 (Box-folder 132/6)
  - August, 1993 (Box-folder 132/7)
  - September, 1993 (Box-folder 132/8)
  - September, 1993 (Box-folder 133/1)
  - October, 1993 (Box-folder 133/2)
  - October, 1993 (Box-folder 133/3)
  - November, 1993 (Box-folder 133/4)
  - November, 1993 (Box-folder 133/5)
  - December, 1993 (Box-folder 133/6)
  - January, 1994 (Box-folder 133/7)
  - January, 1994 (Box-folder 133/8)
  - February, 1994 (Box-folder 134/1)
  - February, 1994 (Box-folder 134/2)
  - March, 1994 (Box-folder 134/3)
  - March, 1994 (Box-folder 134/4)
  - April, 1994 (Box-folder 134/5)
  - April, 1994 (Box-folder 134/6)
  - May, 1994 (Box-folder 135/1)
  - May, 1994 (Box-folder 135/2)
  - June, 1994 (Box-folder 135/3)
  - June, 1994 (Box-folder 135/4)
  - June, 1994 (Box-folder 135/5)
  - August, 1994 (Box-folder 136/1)
  - August, 1994 (Box-folder 136/2)
  - September, 1994 (Box-folder 136/3)
  - September, 1994 (Box-folder 136/4)
  - October, 1994 (Box-folder 136/5)
  - October, 1994 (Box-folder 136/6)
  - October, 1994 (Box-folder 137/1)
  - October, 1994 (Box-folder 137/2)
  - November, 1994 (Box-folder 137/3)
  - November, 1994 (Box-folder 137/4)
  - November, 1994 (Box-folder 137/5)
  - December, 1994 (Box-folder 137/6)
  - January, 1995 (Box-folder 138/1)
  - January, 1995 (Box-folder 138/2)
  - February, 1995 (Box-folder 138/3)
  - February, 1995 (Box-folder 138/4)
  - March, 1995 (Box-folder 138/5)
  - April, 1995 (Box-folder 138/6)
  - May, 1995 (Box-folder 138/7)
  - June, 1995 (Box-folder 139/1)
  - June, 1995 (Box-folder 139/2)
  - July, 1995 (Box-folder 139/3)
  - August, 1995 (Box-folder 139/4)
  - September, 1995 (Box-folder 139/5)
  - October, 1995 (Box-folder 139/6)
  - November, 1995 (Box-folder 139/7)
  - December, 1995 (Box-folder 140/1)
  - January, 1996 (Box-folder 140/2)
  - January, 1996 (Box-folder 140/3)
  - February, 1996 (Box-folder 140/4)
  - March, 1996 (Box-folder 140/5)
  - April, 1996 (Box-folder 140/6)
  - May, 1996 (Box-folder 140/7)
  - June, 1996 (Box-folder 141/1)
  - July, 1996 (Box-folder 141/2)
  - August, 1996 (Box-folder 141/3)
  - September, 1996 (Box-folder 141/4)
  - October, 1996 (Box-folder 141/5)
  - November, 1996 (Box-folder 141/6)
  - 1997 and undated (Box-folder 141/7)
  - Japanese newspaper, date unknown (Box-folder 141/8)
- Accomplishments and Retirement, 1987-1996; Series VII; 1.0 linear foot
  This series consists of materials associated with Williams' accomplishments in office and with his retirement. Materials labeled accomplishments were gathered by his staff and consist of articles, press releases, correspondence, and office memoranda. Retirement materials consist mostly of notes of thanks to and from constituents.
  Materials are arranged chronologically.
  - Accomplishments, 1987-1996 (Box-folder 142/1)
  - Accomplishments, 1994 (Box-folder 142/2)
  - Accomplishments, 1995 (Box-folder 142/3)
  - Accomplishments, 1995 (Box-folder 142/4)
  - Accomplishments, 1995 (Box-folder 142/5)
  - Accomplishments, 1995 (Box-folder 142/6)
  - Congressional Retirement, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 142/7)
  - Congressional Retirement, 1996 (Box-folder 142/8)
  - Congressional Retirement, 1996 (Box-folder 143/1)
  - Congressional Retirement, 1996 (Box-folder 143/2)
- Wilderness, 1979-1980; Series VIII; 6.0 linear feet
  This series contains legislative materials, correspondence, maps, reports and printed material. They represent the attempts by Pat Williams and Staff Member Art Noonan to define areas within the borders of Montana that should receive wilderness protection. Many materials deal directly with the needs of Montana communities and industries throughout the wilderness designation process.
  Included is information from early wilderness debates through the development of the RARE II process and specific wilderness boundaries. Much of the material deals with specific Senate bills and House resolutions, such as S. 1696, S. 2790, S. 489, H.R. 6001, H.R. 2090, H.R. 2473. Additionally, this series contains materials on related issues such as geothermal protection (in H.R. 3359 and H.R. 723, the Old Faithful Protection Act), a proposed repeal of the 1872 mining law (H.R. 918), the Northern Rockies Ecosystems Protection Act, the Nez Perce National Historical Park (H.R. 2032 and S. 550), as well as some materials addressing general land and resource management of public lands. These general public lands materials are housed within the Wilderness Series both as a reflection of the context within which they were received and the subtle distinction between formal wilderness designation and broad wilderness concepts among many private citizens and journalists.
  This series lacks an original cohesive organization schema, as it arrived from Williams' offices in total disarray. During 2003 processing, when possible, materials were organized according to Senate Bill or House Resolution number. Other materials could not be directly associated to a Congressional action; thus, were organized and identified by common geographic designation.
  Additional wilderness materials reside in Series I and II and are identified by their specific Congressional actions or geographic designations. During 2003 processing a sequence of photographs documenting a wilderness designation protest organized by Montanans for Multiple Use was transferred to Series XI: Photographs.
  - H.R. 2090, Statement and Testimonies, 1987 and undated (Box-folder 144/1)
  - H.R. 2090, Proposed Wilderness, 1987 (Box-folder 144/2)
  - H.R. 2090, Correspondence, 1987-1993 (Box-folder 144/3)
  - H.R. 2090, S. 1478, S. 2751, Data and Reports, 1988 (Box-folder 144/4)
  - Data and Reports, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 144/5)
  - Clipping and Press Releases, 1987-1994 (Box-folder 144/6)
  - Wilderness Photos, undated (Box-folder 144/7)
  - Montana Roadless Inventory, Data, and Reports, 1994 and undated (Box-folder 145/1)
  - Correspondence, 1994 and undated (Box-folder 145/2)
  - Testimonies and Statements, 1993-1994 and undated (Box-folder 145/3)
  - Testimonies and Statements, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 145/4)
  - H.R. 2473, Bills and Amendments, 1994 (Box-folder 145/5)
  - Bills and Amendments, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 145/6)
  - West Big Hole, 1979-1981 and undated (Box-folder 146/1)
  - S. 2009, Idaho Wilderness, 1979-1980 and undated (Box-folder 146/2)
  - House Report 98-405, Part I, 1983 (Box-folder 146/3)
  - Early RARE II, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 146/4)
  - H.R. 6001, Eary RARE II, 1987 (Box-folder 146/5)
  - S. 2790, 1986 and undated (Box-folder 146/6)
  - RARE II, 1986-1992 and undated (Box-folder 147/1)
  - RARE II, Maps and Data, 1987 and undated (Box-folder 147/2)
  - General Land Management and Reports, 1981-1994 and undated (Box-folder 147/3)
  - Land and Resource Management, Forest Service Oversight, 1988-1990 and undated (Box-folder 147/4)
  - Land and Resource Management, Forest Service, Resignations of John Mumma and Ernie Nunn, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 147/5)
  - Wilderness Designations, Statements and Petitions, 1992-1995 and undated (Box-folder 147/6)
  - Wilderness Clippings, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 147/7)
  - S. 2751, 1988 and undated (Box-folder 147/8)
  - S. 1478, S. 2751, Bills and Amendments, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 148/1)
  - Conservationist Response to S. 2790, undated (Box-folder 148/2)
  - Order by U.S. Secretary of Agriculture Glickman, 1995 (Box-folder 148/3)
  - Roadless Bill, Statements, Reports, Correspondence and Clippings, 1990 (Box-folder 148/4)
  - Roadless Bill and Amendments, 1990 (Box-folder 148/5)
  - RARE II, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 148/6)
  - History of Release Language, 1979-1994 and undated (Box-folder 148/7)
  - Kootenai-Lolo Forest Accords, 1990-1991 and undated (Box-folder 148/8)
  - General Wilderness, 1998-1994 and undated (Box-folder 149/1)
  - S. 489, Gallatin Range Consolidation and Protection, 1993 and undated (Box-folder 149/2)
  - Plum Creek Land Exchange in the Gallatin Area, 1992-1993 and undated (Box-folder 149/3)
  - H.R. 918, Constituent Letters, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 149/4)
  - S. 1696, Testimonies and Speeches, 1992 (Box-folder 149/5)
  - S. 1696, Bills and Reports, 1991-1993 and undated (Box-folder 149/6)
  - S. 1696, Clippings, News Releases, and Correspondence, 1991-1993 and undated (Box-folder 149/7)
  - S. 1696, WETA Recommendations, 1991 (Box-folder 149/8)
  - S. 1696, Testimonies, Maps, Proposed Bills, 1988-1993 and undated (Box-folder 150/1)
  - S. 1696, Testimonies, Maps, Proposed Bills, 1990-1993 and undated (Box-folder 150/2)
  - S. 1696, Proposed Bills, Testimonies, Speeches, 1992 and undated (Box-folder 150/3)
  - Designation Maps, 1994-1991 and undated (Box-folder 150/4)
  - S. 1696, Constituent Letters, 1991-1992 and undated (Box-folder 151/1)
  - S. 1696, Constituent Letters, 1992-1993 and undated (Box-folder 151/2)
  - S. 1696, Constituent Letters, 1992-1994 and undated (Box-folder 151/3)
  - S. 1696, Constituent Letters, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 151/4)
  - S. 1696, Clippings, 1991-1994 and undated (Box-folder 151/5)
  - H.R. 3359, Speeches and Clippings, 1991 and undated (Box-folder 152/1)
  - H.R. 3359, 1991-1992 and undated (Box-folder 152/2)
  - H.R. 3359, 1987-1991 and undated (Box-folder 152/3)
  - H.R. 3359, 1988-1993 and undated (Box-folder 152/4)
  - Old Faithful Protection Act, H.R. 723, S. 986, H.R. 1137, 1991-1995 and undated (Box-folder 152/5)
  - Northern Rockies Ecosystems Protection Act, 1991-1995 and undated (Box-folder 153/1)